A black and bloody Irish comedy.
Six Shooter is a drama, comedy, crime film directed by Martin McDonagh.
Overwhelmed by grief following the death of his wife, Donnelly shares a train
carriage home with a troubled young man identified only as the 'Kid'.
As the Kid becomes more agitated and foul-mouthed, the journey takes on a violent and dangerous
hue – for the bereaved Donnelly and for other hapless passengers on the train.
Academy Award Winner: Best Live Action Short Film – 2005
Donnelly, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Kid, played by Rúaidhrí Conroy.
Man, played by David Wilmot.
Woman, played by Aisling O'Sullivan.
Chief Guard, played by Gary Lydon.
Cashier, played by Domhnall Gleeson.
Six Shooter is a 2004 short film written and directed by Martin
McDonagh and starring Brendan Gleeson and Rúaidhrí Conroy.
A co-production between the United Kingdom and Ireland, it earned several accolades, including the Academy
Award for Best Live Action Short Film as well as the BAFTA Award for Best Short Film nomination.
The film explores themes of gun, passenger, dark comedy, grief, train.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.